<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ataraxia</title>
    <link>https://vasilogi.github.io/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ataraxia</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2024, Ioannis Vasilopoulos</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 09:47:24 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://vasilogi.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Customise a Multimodal AI for Generating E-Shop Image Descriptions</title>
      <link>https://vasilogi.github.io/post/e-shop-ollama-image-to-text/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Nov 2024 09:47:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vasilogi.github.io/post/e-shop-ollama-image-to-text/</guid>
      <description>Imagine you&amp;rsquo;re an e-shop owner who regularly receives new items from vendors that need to be listed in your online store. This process involves several manual steps, with writing marketing descriptions for each item being the most time-consuming task. To automate this process, various solutions have been considered, and a Multimodal AI model appears to be an excellent solution. These Deep Learning models can process information from multiple modalities, such as images and text simultaneously.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Installing Ollama on Windows and Setting Up Open WebUI</title>
      <link>https://vasilogi.github.io/post/llama-openwebui-on-windows/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Nov 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vasilogi.github.io/post/llama-openwebui-on-windows/</guid>
      <description>This article demonstrates how to install Ollama and Open WebUI on your local machine to self-host and interact with Generative AI models.&#xA;For optimal performance, it&amp;rsquo;s recommended to install Ollama natively on your machine. Download the installer from the official website and follow the installation instructions. Once installed, launch Ollama and let it run in the background. Ollama provides a Command Line Interface (CLI) that enables you to manage compatible models, including pulling/pushing from a registry, viewing installed models, and creating new ones.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building Your Own Iot Monitoring Solution</title>
      <link>https://vasilogi.github.io/post/building-own-iot-monitoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Apr 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vasilogi.github.io/post/building-own-iot-monitoring/</guid>
      <description>📝 Introduction The Internet of Things (IoT) market is rapidly expanding, with revenues expected to reach $947.50 billion in 2024 worldwide and projected to grow to $1,560.00 billion by 2029, according to Statista. This growth spans across consumer, industrial, automotive, smart cities, and smart finance sectors, with automotive IoT leading the way.&#xA;In the IoT ecosystem, monitoring and dash-boarding are crucial for real-time data visualization, anomaly detection, and proactive maintenance. While numerous commercial solutions exist, building your own monitoring system can offer unique advantages in flexibility, cost-effectiveness, and data privacy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>whoami: Ioannis, Giannis, or Yannis? 🇬🇷 issues.</title>
      <link>https://vasilogi.github.io/post/whoami/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vasilogi.github.io/post/whoami/</guid>
      <description>If you are reading this, chances are you&amp;rsquo;re one of my colleagues. Hello there 🤗&#xA;Perhaps you have noticed me sending private messages as Giannis, or Yannis. However, in official documents and professional settings, my name is listed as &amp;ldquo;Ioannis&amp;rdquo; 🤔&#xA;Unfortunately, I don&amp;rsquo;t possess multiple identities 😄 My name is officially Ιωάννης, which directly translates to English as Ioannis. However, this sounds too formal in common Greek, and thus its diminutive form, Γιάννης, is preferred.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Why blogging?</title>
      <link>https://vasilogi.github.io/post/why_blogging/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Feb 2024 20:38:18 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://vasilogi.github.io/post/why_blogging/</guid>
      <description>There&amp;rsquo;s undoubtedly an abundance of blogs and content about software and AI, which are currently my main interests. One might wonder why the world needs another such blog. The answer is simple: why not! I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to start blogging (even if sporadically) for three main reasons: to enhance my writing, illustration, and communication skills; to share my interests with others; and to maintain focus through the discipline of writing.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
